对付敌人最好的武器
就是另一个敌人
— 弗里德里希·尼采（1844年--1900年）
罗马尼亚 布加勒斯特
影片压制：andydexin   字幕转制：木子丁
====  N O R M  T E A M  ====
译文源自TLF字幕组
我想敬一杯酒
I want to propose a toast.
今天对我来讲是个特别的日子…
Today is a very special day
for me...
…有点紧张 所以 我把想说的话写了下来
...so I'm nervous,
and I wrote down my speech.
我要把这杯酒敬给这个世界上最仁慈…
A toast to the kindest, most gentle...
…最绅士 最出色的男人：
...and most wonderful man
in the world:
我的父亲
Papa.
感谢您让我梦想成真
Thank you for making my dream
come true.
下面 大家开始跳舞吧
And now maybe let's dance.
站住
Stop.
没问题
He's okay.
- 喂！你怎么搞的？  - 不好意思 非常不好意思
- Hey! What are you doing?  - Sorry. I'm so sorry.
我再去拿几条毛巾 很快回来
I'll get more towels. Be right back.
伊凡·波利萨维奇？
Ivan Borisovich?
伊凡·波利萨维奇
Ivan Borisovich!
老大遇刺了 凶手是个乔装成侍者的家伙
The boss is down!
The hitter's dressed like a waiter!
守住所有出口 守住所有出口
Cover all exits! Cover all exits!
萨沙 萨沙 他在朝你的方向跑
Sasha! Sasha!
He's heading your way!
萨沙
Sasha!
萨沙 听到没有？
Sasha, you hear me?
萨沙？
Sasha?
片名：刺杀游戏（又名：刺客对决）
你说过不会再出岔子了
You told me
there'll be no loose ends.
- 我知道是谁搞的鬼了  - 谁？
- We got it down to one.  - Who?
弗林特
Flint.
你们有最好的装备…
You have access to the best
technology...
…却让一个拖着个昏迷老婆的家伙逃了——
...and yet a man with a comatose
wife in tow can elude you for--
这都多少年了？
For how many years now?
就算他再强也该逃到头了
This is what he does best,
and he is the best.
他也是外界唯一一个能把我们除掉的
He's also the only one outside
this room who can bury us.
好了 各位 来 我们好好想想
Okay, guys, look, let's think.
弗里特真的有那么大的威胁吗？
Is Flint really that much
of a problem?
我是说他一出现 我们就可以轻易干掉他
I mean, look, if he shows,
we can easily take him out.
既然你有主意了 就去干掉那个混蛋吧
You had a good idea to start.
Get rid of the bad guys.
雇个靠谱的人 我出钱 好吧
Hire professionals for the job.
Fine. I backed you.
但是你们两个蠢货得从贪得无厌的
军火买卖回到正经事上来
But then you two idiots got greedy
selling weapons back to criminals.
嘿 你也分到钱了
Hey, you got your share.
闭嘴
Shut up.
关于你们这堆麻烦事的联合国听证会…
The U.N. hearings
about this whole mess of yours...
…这个月月底召开
...start at the end of the month.
如果有任何闪失 无论是什么…
If there's any fallout,
any problem whatsoever...
…我保证我会把这盆脏水统统泼到你们头上
...I promise I will land this clusterfuck
squarely on your shoulders.
你们俩后半辈子就都得给我蹲大牢
And you both will spend the rest
of your natural lives behind bars.
好了 知道了
Okay. We get it.
但愿你是真的明白了 也是为你自己好
For your sake, I hope you do.
因为我听说 监狱里那些可爱的条子手段多着呢
Because I hear they just love
cute, dirty cops in prison.
- 混蛋  - 但他是个精明的混蛋
- Asshole.  - But he's a smart asshole.
为了保全自己 他会毫不犹豫地除掉我们
And he'll waste no time burying us
to protect himself.
- 那么 我们该怎么办？  - 找到弗林特
- So, what do we do?  - Find Flint.
干掉他
Take him out.
怎么干掉他？
How?
上哪找比他更强的杀手去
He was the best on our payroll.
- 你自己也是这么说的  - 我们可以用诱饵
- You said so yourself.  - We use bait.
你是说保罗
You mean Polo.
我们收买乌克兰人 放了保罗 再悬赏他
We pay off the Ukrainians,
release Polo, put a price on his head.
但你凭什么认为弗林特会就此现身？
What makes you think Flint'll show?
这跟他的私人恩怨有关 他烦这个很久了
我们可以利用这一点
It's personal, he's obsessed.
Let's use that.
这是我们唯一的机会了
It's our only play.
乌克兰 喀尔巴阡山脉
早上好 弗林特先生
Good morning, Mr. Flint.
我去诊所上早班了
I've got the morning shift
at the clinic.
等一下 帕瓦勒斯夫人
Hang on, Mrs. Pavlescu.
我只是想把这个给你
I just wanted to give you this.
哦 谢谢 你太好了
Oh, thank you.
You are much too kind.
- 总是这样  - 这没有什么 安娜和我…
- As always.  - Please. Anna and I...
我们欠你的比这多得多
We owe you a lot more than that.
说实话 没有你我们真的不知道该怎么办
Honestly, I don't know
what we'd do without you.
- 过的愉快  - 谢谢
- Have a good day.  - Thank you.
哦 我差点忘了
Oh, almost forgot.
我昨天去了趟杂货铺…
I was getting groceries yesterday...
…店里的盖比说城里来了个男人
...and Gabi at the store
said there was a man in town.
- 什么样的男人？  - 一个外国人
- What man?  - A foreigner.
他住在汽车旅馆
He's staying at the motel.
我觉得你可能会对这感兴趣
I thought you'd like to know.
好的 谢了 帕瓦勒斯夫人
Okay, thanks, Mrs. Pavlescu.
再见
Bye.
你是怎么找到我的？
How did you find me?
- 见到你我也很高兴  - 我在问你 你是怎么找到我的？
- Good to see you too.  - How did you find me?
我不会再问一遍
I'm not gonna ask you again.
不过是凭直觉
It was just a hunch.
我不可能会被人跟踪
There's no way
I could have been followed.
是安娜…
Anna...
她告诉过我你们俩 在这里初识时有多么相爱
Anna told me how much you two loved
coming up here when you first met.
我开车搜寻过 从这里 到奥地利边境间的所有村庄
I've been driving through every village
between here and the Austrian border.
你找我想干什么？
What do you want'?
- 有份工作  - 我金盆洗手了
- There's a job.  - I'm out of the business.
- 酬金一百万  - 我不缺那些钱
- Ticket's a million.  - I don't need the money.
要是再让我看见你…
I see you again...
…就叫你家里人给你收尸吧
...I'm sending you home in a box.
目标是保罗
Target's Polo.
他已经被释放了
He's being released.
被释放了？
Released?
乌克兰人放了他
The Ukrainians are letting him go.
我敢保证他要么做了笔什么交易
要么出卖了谁 差不多就这种事儿
I'm willing to bet he either out a deal
or snitched on someone. Whatever.
- 又或者他只是个诱饵  - 针对你的？
- Or he's bait.  - For you?
新政策出台了 国际刑警组织可能要清理门户
New administration.
Maybe Interpol cleaning house.
但他们还是想弄回他们的钱 我是说 你…
They still want their money back.
I mean, you did--
罗兰 别这样
Roland, don't.
为什么不？
Why not?
因为没人跟踪我 我也不是在陷害你
Because I wasn't followed.
Because I'm not setting you up.
我只是觉得我们可以合作赚笔钱 你明白吗？
I just thought we could make
a few bucks together, you know?
打开音乐
Turn on the music.
- 什么？  - 打开收音机
- What?  - The radio.
开大点儿
Louden
罗兰 拜托
Roland, come on.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
- 你在这片树林里呆得太久了  - 给我闭上眼睛 马上
- You've been in these woods too long.  - Close your eyes now.
罗兰 别冲动 好好想想
Roland, think about
what you're doing, man.
好好想一想 行吗？
Just think about it, will you?
我是说 我不是在陷害你
这些年来我什么不该说的也没说过
I mean, I'm not setting you up.
All these years I didn't say nothing.
拜托 想一想 我们在这里呆了太久了
I mean, come on, man, just think.
We've got a history here.
罗兰？
Roland?
欢迎你 我的朋友
Welcome, my friend.
俄罗斯的任务干得相当漂亮
The Russian project
went perfectly.
波加利亚人送来了他们的谢礼
The Bulgarians send their thanks.
- 巧克力要么？  - 太容易发胖了
- Chocolate?  - Too fattening.
那好吧 不过我这有你无法拒绝的好东西
Very well, but I have goodies
you cannot refuse.
老规矩 南美货 特别切工
Your usual.
South African, special cut.
现在准确的市值是…
Today's value exactly...
…55万
...550,000.
额外的5万是奖励
The extra 5O is a bonus.
客户们都十分满意
The clients are extremely happy.
我的目标就是使人满意
I aim to please.
还有个更好的消息 是另一个待定的合同
And even better news,
another potential contract.
酬金是你平常价码的两倍
Double your usual fee.
目标是谁？
Who's the mark?
保罗·雅克 一位出身名门 声誉良好的绅士
Polo Yakur. A well-connected
gentleman of some reputation.
他在监狱里
He's in prison.
- 这会很麻烦  - 但他今天已经被释放了
- It will be a difficult job.  - He's being released today.
我会尽快给你更多细节
I'll have more details shortly.
- 那么客户是谁？  - 他不想透漏身份
- And the client?  - Wishes to remain anonymous.
我接手了
I'll take it.
我就知道你会这么说
I was hoping you'd say that.
我想知道如果有一天你觉得赚够了钱…
I wonder if one day you'll feel
you've made enough money...
…会不会考虑搬到一个好点的地方去
...to move to a better neighborhood.
我喜欢我住的地方
I like my neighborhood.
不要多管闲事
People mind their own business.
当然
Of course.
嘿 伙计们
Hey, boys.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
我弟弟呢？
Where's my brother?
- 抱歉 老大 他被捕了  - 什么时候？
- Sorry, boss. He got picked up.  - When?
上个礼拜 有些家伙太多嘴了
Last week.
Some guy talked too much.
走吧
Let's drive.
罗兰
Roland.
罗兰 救我 罗兰
Roland, help. Roland!
罗兰
Roland.
罗兰 罗兰
Roland. Roland.
罗兰 救我
Roland, help!
罗兰
Roland.
少废话 等我回来的时候这些破东西
最好都还在里面 没拆封
Bullshit. When I'm back all this shit
better be inside, unpacked.
你最好也穿戴好了准备去工作 懂吗？
And you'd better be dressed
to go to work, understand?
听明白了吗？
Do you understand?
嘿 你好吗？
Hey, how you doing?
我和奥克图波尔是你的新邻居
We're your new neighbors.
October and me.
那是你家？
That your place?
是的
Yeah.
喏 我正打算拓展我的业务…
See, I'm looking
into expanding my business...
…想把整层楼买下来
...and I'm thinking
about buying the whole ﬂoor.
我不会让你吃亏的 明白吗？
I'd make it worth your while, huh?
是吗
I doubt it.
他妈看什么看？把箱子搬进去
What the fuck you looking at?
Move the boxes.
- 喂  - 是我 我想加入
- Hello.  - it's me. I want in.
- 我要接保罗的活儿  - 已经有人接了
- I'll take the Polo job.  - it's off the market.
赏金一百万 重赏之下必有勇夫
A million bucks
is a tough ticket to keep open.
我不在乎那些钱
I don't care about the money.
让我干就行 再替我准备些装备
Just get me the intel,
maybe some gear.
这主意糟透了
It's a bad idea.
我可不想成为别人的眼中钉
We don't want to get
in someone's way.
这种钱是牵涉到一些大人物的
This type of money,
there's serious people involved.
克里 你还欠我的
Culley. You owe me.
这样 我很抱歉去找你了 行了吗？
Look, I'm sorry
for looking for you, all right?
低调点
Just lay low.
你很安全 安娜也是
You're safe. Anna's safe.
这样的日子还能过多久？
How long is that gonna last?
我拿他的一半装备把保罗引出来
I took out half his outfit
and put Polo away.
他好接替我完成任务
He's gonna come after me
to finish the job.
不对 最好是让我先揍他一顿
No, it's better if I hit him first.
拜托 帮帮我
Come on, man.
I need your help here.
好吧 好吧
All right, all right.
- 你可以搬过来住  - 很好
- You can come stay here.  - That's good.
- 一会儿见  - 好的
- See you soon.  - Yeah.
我绝对是疯了
I should have my head examined.
又来了 好像保罗的弟弟 丹佐…
Here. Looks like
Polo's brother, Danzo...
…明天会接受审讯
...is gonna walk
at the trial tomorrow.
但目击证人神秘失踪了
The prosecution's witness
is mysteriously missing.
这是个好机会 运气好的话 保罗会亲自来保释他
That's our shot. Now, if we're lucky,
Polo comes to get him in person.
好 我们把这消息放出去吧
Okay, let's leak it out.
好主意 弗林特会闻风而动的
Good idea. Flint'll have
his ears to the ground.
我的线人说我们的朋友明天会造访…
My sources say our friend
might be visiting...
…一座市中心的法庭
...a downtown courthouse tomorrow.
将
Checkmate.
你真是迅雷不及掩耳啊
You are full of surprises, my friend.
市法院
Municipal courthouse.
嗯
Yup.
- 情报可靠吗？  - 绝对可靠
- How good's the intel?  - Solid.
老法子 双盲测试
Double-blind, the usual.
说不定还是你在国际警察组织的老朋友
Could be your old friends
from Interpol.
你确定你要干到底吗？
Sure you wanna go through with it?
妈 别为我担心了
Don't worry about me, Mom.
我之前干过一两次
I've done this once or twice before.
看中什么了？
You see something you like?
丹佐
Danzo.
丹佐 丹佐 能听见我说话吗？
Danzo. Danzo. Can you hear me?
看着我 看着我 丹佐 丹佐
Look at me. Look at me, Danzo.
Danzo.
枪手在货车里 枪手在货车里
Shooter in the van.
那个混账东西杀了我弟弟
The motherfucker shot my brother.
请镇定一下
Please settle down.
你他妈的还说什么“镇定”？
What the fuck you mean
"settle down"?
操
Fuck.
丹佐 小心 护好他的头
Danzo. Careful. Watch his head.
快点 救护车呢？
Come on. Where's the ambulance?
快点 快点
Come on. Come on.
把枪放下
Gun.
快走
GO, go!
站住 喂 别动
Stop. Hey you, freeze.
- 站住  - 站住
- Stop, stop, StOP-  - Stop, stop.
让开
Move, move, move.
- 我们死定了  - 不 我们没有
- We're dead.  - No, we're not.
计划成功了 我们把弗林特引出来了
It's working. We drew Flint out.
- 你不觉得我们打草惊蛇了吗？  - 他看见你了吗？
- You don't think we spooked him?  - You see his face?
我们已经引他上钩了 保罗不死他是不会罢休的
We've got him hooked.
He won't quit till Polo's dead.
但我们需要更多的枪和装备
We need more guns, hardware.
- 我们没法单干  - 说得对 是时候去找哈罗德了
- We can't do this alone.  - Good point. Time to call Herrod.
我和医生谈过了
I talked to the doctor.
这支箭箭尖有毒 毒效非常快
It was poison-tipped.
Very fast-acting.
他说制造者了解这种毒性
He said whoever did this
knows his toxins.
把它保存好…
Keep it safe...
…等我找到了那个杀了我弟弟的畜生…
...so when I find the animal
that killed my brother...
…我要用这个挖出他的眼睛
...I can use it to carve out his eyes.
我就知道没什么好事
I don't believe in fairy tales.
他们一告诉我我被释放了…
The minute they told me
I was being released...
…我就嗅到了不祥的气息
...I smelled something rotten.
我认为那个逃走的狙击手…
I don't think either
the sniper that missed...
…或者罗宾汉出现在那里不是个巧合
...or Robin Hood
was there by coincidence.
也许我们应该低调一点
今晚我们恐怕上了同一条船
Maybe you should lay low.
We could be on a boat tonight.
在找到杀死丹佐的凶手前我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere
until I find who killed Danzo.
来吧 我们有活儿干了
Come on, we have work to do.
现在我们知道了这是一个阴谋
Now we know it was a setup.
我要打几个电话 在今晚之前把你送出国
I'll make calls,
have you out of the country by tonight.
- 我会处理好的  - 不
- I'll handle it.  - No.
查一查保罗的侄子是不是还管着
码头边的那些工厂
Find out if Polo's cousin
still owns those factories by the docks.
你确定？
You sure about that?
- 是的  - 好的 我去查查
- Yeah.  - All right. I'll make some calls.
没人敢这样跟我说话
Nobody talks shit to me.
你却老是顶嘴
You always got something to say.
再顶几句屁话啊 死贱货
Talk some more shit to me.
Stupid bitch.
- 别打了  - 够了
- Stop it.  - That's enough.
你还顶嘴？
You still got something to say?
你吵到我了
You're disturbing me.
哪凉快哪呆着去
Go and cool off.
滚
Go.
你还好吗？
You Okay?
不好
No.
对不起
Excuse me.
我正要练琴呢
I'm trying to practice.
我被锁在外面了
I'm locked out.
坐
Sit.
敷上这个 会有用的
Put this on. It will help.
- 喂？  - 尽管你碰到了无法预见的困难…
- Hello?  - Despite your unforeseen difficulties...
- …这合同你还是别管了  - 等一下
-...the contract remains open.  - Wait.
别动 在那呆着 好吗？
Don't move. Stay there. Okay?
那还有另一个枪手 我原以为这是独家的任务
There was another shooter.
I thought it was exclusive.
这是独家的任务 客户已经确认了
但还有第三方参与了进来
It is. The client has confirmed
that a third party may be involved.
第三方是因为个人恩怨而牵涉进来的
A third party with personal issues.
我还知道几个保罗的朋友可能出没的地点
I also have a possible location
for our polo-playing friend.
你现在得走了
You need to leave now.
我被锁在外面了
I'm locked out.
你可以在走廊等着
You can wait in the hallway.
求求你
Please.
拜托 你现在必须得走
Come on, you have to go now.
求求你了 我能在这待一晚吗？
Please, can I stay here
just for tonight?
拜托 出去吧
Come on, out.
要等到明天他才会冷静下来
It'll take him till tomorrow
to calm down.
他要是现在看到我 又要打我了
He sees me now,
he'll put me in the hospital again.
你明早必须走 好吗？
You need to be gone
in the morning, okay?
还有 别碰我的东西
And don't touch anything.
保罗的合同是我的 我一个人的
The Polo contract is mine.
Exclusive.
我不在乎酬金 这关乎我的私人恩怨
I don't care about the money.
It's personal.
你让我失去了酬金 这也关乎我的私人利益
You lose me my fee,
it's personal to me.
你确定那些你老古董还管用吗
Sure those antiques still work?
- 只有一个办法确认  - 你就是法院那边的那个人
- One way to find out.  - You're the guy from the courthouse.
- 你阻挡我射击了  - 你也让我射失了
- Blocked my shot.  - You made me miss.
真的吗？
Touché.
听着 我们都是行家
Look, we're both professionals.
总能达成某种共识
Sure we can come to some sort
of understanding.
我只觉得你在碍我的事
What I understand
is you're getting in my way.
这正是我想说的 我们在追击同一个目标…
Exactly my point.
We keep chasing the same target...
…总会碍另一个人的事
...we'll keep getting
in each other's way.
所以你要是识相的话就给我出局
Then stay out of it.
法庭那次混乱后 保罗现在肯定全副武装了
After that mess at the courthouse,
Polo's gonna be on full guard.
除掉他的最好的办法就是我们俩合作
The best way for us to get him
is if we work together.
这样你还是能拿到酬金 伙计 对不对？
You get the money
either way, pal. All right?
不光能拿到全额酬金 还多了个免费的帮手
The whole million.
And a free pair of hands.
没人会做赔本买卖 你究竟图什么？
Nothing in life is for free.
What's in it for you?
我跟保罗有旧账要算
I got history with Polo.
嗯 很好 一个背负深仇的搭档
Oh, great. A partner with a vendetta.
正是我想要的
Just what I need.
你找不到他的 我能找到
You'll never find him. I will.
这事我已经忙活了很久了
I've been doing this
for a long time, my friend.
哦 你这样下去最终是会找到他的
但我今天晚上就能找到他
Oh, you'll find him eventually.
I'll find him tonight.
我说过的 我跟他有旧账要算
Like I said, I got history with Polo.
我花了两年时间打入他内部
I spent two years of my life
infiltrating his crew.
他再也不会回这来
He's never gonna come back here.
他会断绝过去的一切来往 除了其中一个
He will sever all his usual contacts
except for one.
- 谁？  - 你这算是同意合作了？
- Who?  - We got a deal?
如果你的情报是真的 是哪来的？
If your intel's for real.
Who's your lead?
那个给保罗造军火的家伙
The guy who makes his hardware.
保罗最喜欢他的产品
Polo loves his toys.
我读到过这玩意儿
I read about these things.
很酷
Very cool.
小心点
Careful.
小心点 那台设备值50万
Careful, that's a half-a-million-dollar
piece of equipment.
口气真像个商人
Spoken like a true businessman.
但你该问的问题是…
But the question
you should be asking...
…枪里是不是有子弹
...is whether the weapon is loaded.
等等 不 不要
Wait, wait, wait. No, don't.
天啊 好吧 嘿 好吧
God, okay. Hey. Okay.
你想要什么？
What do you want'?
天啊
Holy shit.
罗兰·弗林特
Roland Flint.
你还记得我 很好
You remember me, that's good.
你知道我要什么
And you know what I want.
你就是那个打电话来的人
You're the one who called.
- 现在没工作吗？  - 别扯东扯西
- So there's no job?  - Quit stalling.
我不知道他在哪
I have no idea where he is.
听着 我听说这玩意儿还能大规模散射
You know, I read these things
can even memorize a pattern.
不 停下 嘿 别这样
No, no, stop. Hey, stop.
No, hey. Stop.
好的 好的 放心 我不会杀你的
All right, all right. Calm down.
I'm not gonna kill you.
只是会把你炸成一块一块的
Just gonna blow you apart
limb by limb.
求求你了 我家上有老下有小
Please, I have a family.
我也有家室 你这白痴
I had a family too, you piece of shit.
好的 好的 我告诉你
Okay, okay, hey. I'll tell you.
快讲
Talk fast.
我会告诉你的
I'll tell you.
他知道他被悬赏了
He knows he's got a price
on his head.
所以现在轮流住在
以前用作前沿阵地的几家旅馆
He's moving around hotels
he once used as a front.
- 给我地址  - 我不知道他现在在哪一家
- Give me an address.  - I don't know where he is right now.
但周四周五他会在皇家大酒店
But Thursday and Friday
he'll be at the Royal Grand.
要是你没说实话…
If you're lying to me...
我明白 我知道你会怎么做 行行好
I understand. I know what you do.
Please.
好
Good.
你他妈在搞什么？
What the hell was that?
什么搞什么？
What the hell was what?
为什么要杀了他？我想让他活着
Why did you kill him?
I wanted the guy alive.
我有一个计划
I had a plan.
我要把你介绍给他 让他跑到保罗那里…
I was gonna introduce you.
He was gonna run off to Polo...
…带给他关于杀死他弟弟的凶手的线索…
...with a line on the guy
that killed his brother...
…这样我就可以诱他出来
...and I was gonna use that
to lure him in.
你没告诉过我啊
You didn't tell me that.
因为这是个新主意 行了吗？
Because it was a new idea,
all right?
我随时在思考
I was thinking on the fly.
如果你想要一个搭档…
If you want a partner...
…你必须得学会沟通
...you've got to learn
how to communicate better.
你知道的 你应该为有一个引路人而感到庆幸
You know, you're lucky
we have a lead.
- 你信任他吗？  - 就像我信任你一样
- You trust him?  - As much as I trust you.
我会让我的手下去确认他的信息 行吗？
I'll get my people
to confirm his info, okay?
好的 你去查吧 我去查皇家大酒店的布局
Yeah, you do that. I'll get
the layout for the Royal Grand.
然后我们再碰个面 商量清楚
We'll meet, figure it out.
这值50万？
Half a million for this?
你知道的 我们得拿走这个
You know, we should just take that.
好让这里的状况看起来像一场入室抢劫
Probably better to make it look
like a break-in anyway.
我们能拿个轻点的东西吗？
Can we take something lighter?
什么事？
What?
我联系到一个在法庭现场的人
I reached out to a guy
at the courthouse.
从一个监控摄相机中找到了这个
Got this off a security camera.
把这个给所有人看 所有人
Get this out to everybody.
I mean everybody.
找到这个混蛋 干掉他
Let's find this fucker and bury him.
醒醒
Wake up.
- 起来 出去  - 对不起
- Come on. Get out.  - Sorry.
你门没关 我看到了水果
You left the door open.
I saw the fruit.
我饿了
L got hungry-
好的 你吃了 睡了 现在该出去了 起来
Okay, you ate, you slept.
Now you're going out. Come on.
快点 出去
Come on. Get out.
- 出去  - 好
- Get out.  - Fine.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
好好活 小乌龟
Have a good life, turtle.
你是怎么做到的？
How did you do that?
- 做什么？  - 你是怎么让他把头伸出来的？
- Do what?  - How did you get him to come out?
过来 我做给你看
Come here. I'll show you.
你只需要抚摸它这里
You just have to pet him right here.
不可思议
Amazing.
等一下
Wait.
你背上应该敷点药
You should put something
on your back.
疼吗？
It hurt?
怎么了？
What?
去接安娜
Go get Anna.
离开这个国家
Get out of the country.
最好去美国
Better yet, go to the States.
我要眼看着这件事完结
I gotta see this through.
你只是要看着它完结吗？
You gotta see it through?
还是你想亲自了结此事？
Or you wanna be the one
who pulls the trigger?
我是说 你说过那个家伙很不错 对吗？很不错
I mean, you said this other
guy's good, right? Good.
他拿到了合同 他是个行家 很有行动力
He's got the contract.
He's a pro, he's motivated.
让他去解决保罗
Let him take care of Polo.
不只是保罗的问题 好吗？
It's not just Polo though, is it?
是那些卑鄙的陷害我的国际刑警
他们对我恨之入骨
It's those dirty Interpol cops that set
me up. They want my head on a stick.
他们想拿回他们的钱 不拿到誓不罢休
They want their money back. They're
gonna keep coming till they get it.
那么 你要怎么做呢？跟他们所有人较量？
So, what are you gonna do?
You take them all on?
你疯了
You're insane.
你可以坐在那里骂骂咧咧 要不然就帮我
You can sit there
insulting me or you can help.
你选什么？
What's it gonna be?
好吧 你要我做什么？
All right. What?
我要去睡了 你过来吗？
I'm going to bed. You coming up?
马上
In a minute.
我知道你从来不会亲自上阵
I know you like
to keep your hands clean.
但是我保证…
But I promise...
…要是你继续让你那些狗腿子咬着我不放
我还会回来
...if you don't get your pit bulls off my
back, I'm gonna come back here.
我会把你老婆的心挖出来让你吃下去 懂吗？
I'll carve your wife's heart out
and make you eat it. Understand?
我没有…
I'm not...
不 你没有听明白
No, you're not listening.
- 永别了  - 不要
- Goodbye.  - Don't.
在我的家里！
In my home!
他就在我自己家里用我在楼上的家人威胁我！
He threatened me in my own home
with my family upstairs!
他只是想吓唬你
Well, he's just trying
to psych you out.
你想要更多人力物力 可以
You want resources, fine.
我会给你额外的人手 武器 无论什么
I'll give you extra men,
weapons, whatever.
但是我要他的命 不管要付出什么代价
But I want him dead.
I don't care what it takes.
我只要他在48小时内给我去死
I just want him dead
in the next 48 hours.
否则我就亲自告发你们两个
Or I will personally turn
the two of you in.
或许我们计划的问题在于…
You know, maybe the problem
with our plan is that...
…保罗没有真正参与进来
...Polo isn't in on it.
你要跟那个疯子合作？
You wanna make that headcase
our partner?
恭候多时了
I've been expecting you.
你就是纳尔班迪安？
You Nalbandian?
愿意为您效劳
At your service.
我想知道悬赏者是谁 是谁陷害的我
I want to know who
the players are. Who set it up.
还有刺杀者是谁 所有一切
Who the hitters are. Everything.
而且我知道你什么都知道
And I know that you know.
就算你是对的 那又怎样？
Let's imagine
that you are right. Now what?
老实交待 免得我动手
Now you tell me
before I start hurting you.
你名不虚传啊
Your reputation is well-deserved.
可我也是 先生
So is mine. Gentlemen.
戈弗雷特工
Agent Godfrey.
我觉得你的计策没有什么长进
I see that your schemes
aren't getting any smarter.
这就是我们为什么需要你
Which is why we need your help.
真的？
Really?
我凭什么帮你？
Why would I help you?
不妨听听…
Immunity. Lifetime guarantee...
…终身享有欧盟和美国的保障
...by both the E.U.
and the U.S. governments.
同时 还可以无条件地飞往…
No strings attached
except a one-way ticket...
…欧美以外 其他任何地区
...to anywhere outside
of Europe and North America.
交换条件是…？
In exchange for...?
帮我们截击罗兰·弗林特
Helping to intercept Roland Flint.
弗林特
Flint.
状况开始变得正常点了
Things begin to make
a little more sense.
这是一份限时的交易 我们必须现在得到答复
It's a limited-time offer.
We need to know.
现在
Now.
- 只有一个条件  - 什么
- One condition.  - What?
我要那个杀了我弟弟的人
I want the man
who killed my brother.
没门
Impossible.
除非你出个好价钱
Unless the price is right.
觉得好点了没有？
You feel better?
我想我得到新的泰利斯了
I guess I got new Tellys now.
什么？
What?
我的伤疤
My scars.
谁给我这个疤 我就管它叫谁的名字
I name them after the man
who gave them to me.
你在对我评头论足
You're judging me.
就好像你比我好多少似的
Like you're so much better.
如果有人给你足够的钱 你会杀我吗？
Would you kill me if someone
offered you enough money?
你想要什么？
What do you want'?
什么也没有
Nothing.
当人们选择他们如何去生时
就已经选择了他们如何去死
People choose their death
when they choose how they live.
这点托辞就能让你夜里安然入睡吗？
Does that let you sleep at night?
我睡得很好
I sleep fine.
我只是一件武器
I'm a weapon.
我不能选择我指向哪
I don't choose where I'm pointed.
当然啦 你只是任人摆布
Of course. You just follow orders.
我和医生跟作家没什么区别
I'm not different
than a doctor or a waiter.
都只是为一项功能服务
I serve a function.
我明白了
I get it.
我也在服务业工作
I'm in the service industry too.
你拿我当娼妓？
You calling me a whore?
不过是服务提供者
A service provider.
事实上我和你一点也不一样
Actually I'm nothing like you.
我别无选择 我一无所有 无依无靠
I don't have a choice.
I have nothing and no one.
你有钱有权
You have money, power.
你随时可以洗手不干
You can get out of the life
anytime you want.
你却没有这样选
You choose not to.
我要出去了
I'm going out.
嘿 你用了我的东西 得付钱
Hey. You cost me business.
她跟你玩完了
She's done with you.
别惹我
You don't want me as an enemy.
你当我是小女孩那么好吓唬吗
I bet that scares the girls.
他是谁？
Who is he?
我们发现这个家伙在附近打探你的下落
Some guy we found snooping
around, asking about you.
我觉得他不是警察
I don't think he's a cop.
你是谁？
Who are you?
圣诞老人
Santa Claus.
哦 很好
Oh, good.
一小丑
A comedian.
再问一遍
Once more.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你聋了吗？我说了我是圣诞老人
Are you deaf? I'm Santa Claus.
聋了
Deaf.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
有新活儿了
We have a new offer.
客户出两倍的价 任务又轻松
The client will double your usual fee
for a fraction of the work.
你要做的只是带你的新朋友…
What you need to do
is bring your new friend...
…在一个特别的时间去一个特别的地方
...to a specific place
at a specific time.
行不通
It will never work.
- 他会察觉的  - 有保罗做诱饵
- He will smell the trap.  - Polo would be there as an incentive.
你只需要领他进去 就可以放手不管了
You will lead him in.
Put him at ease.
要做的就只有这些 一旦开始 你就不用管了
That's all you have to do.
Once it starts, you're out.
朋友是个好东西
It's good to have friends.
但这种危险的朋友还是没有的好
But this is a dangerous friend
to have.
他是个我行我素不顾后果的人
对他来讲 这只是私人恩怨
He's a loose cannon.
For him, it's personal.
弗林特给保罗的组织搞了很多破坏
Flint did a lot of damage
to Polo's organization.
但他的失误在于没切中七寸
But his mistake was leaving
the snake's head for last.
但保罗抓住了弗林特的要害
Polo got Flint where it hurt most.
就是家人 为了给他的对头敲个警钟
Family. Wanted to send a strong
message to his enemies.
他让弗林特看着…
So he made Flint watch...
…他和他的手下轮奸他的妻子…
...while he and his men
gang-raped his wife...
…再把她打昏
...and beat her into a coma.
你的新朋友运气不错 当地警方握着保罗的把柄…
Lucky for your new friend, the local
gendarmes had a tail on Polo...
…在弗林特被干掉前出面干涉
...and intervened
before Flint was killed.
于是他就此销声匿迹
Then Flint vanished.
还卷跑了国际刑警组织一大笔赃款
Along with a sizable chunk
of lnterpol's dirty money.
所以说悬赏保罗不过是障眼法
So this whole job on Polo
is a smoke screen.
那些卑鄙的条子是拿保罗当诱饵
好干掉弗林特 懂吗？
It's dirty cops using Polo
as bait to get Mr. Flint, right?
但酬金是货真价实的
The money is real.
定金三分之一 完事后付清余额
A third now. The rest on completion.
很好
Good.
我还担心弗林特的仇恨会传染给你呢
I was worried Mr. Flint's
personal vendetta was infectious.
- 我要把他带到哪去？  - 市政厅
- Where do I take him?  - City hall.
明天 九点
Tomorrow, 9:00.
明天九点 在市政厅
City hall tomorrow at 9:00.
我的线人说保罗明天要在那 见一个他收买的议员
My source says Polo's meeting
a councilman he's got on his payroll.
消息可靠吗？
Trust your source?
像你一样可靠
As much as I trust you.
- 我有点不放心你  - 怎么？
- I worry about you.  - What?
我担心你会被仇恨冲昏头脑
I'm worried
because for you it's personal.
你太用力了
You care too much.
这会让你送命的 说不定还会搭上我的
It's going to get you dead.
Maybe me too.
扪心自问：
Ask yourself this:
如果你从来没有打心底在乎一个人 或一件事…
If you never really cared about
anyone or anything...
…那么你还是真真切切的活着吗？
...then were you ever really alive?
你这话讲得很像我认识的一个人
You sound like someone I know.
好的 市政厅不错
Yeah, city hall's good.
大厅是他进来的必经之路
那里有很多有利的制高点
The only way in is through the main
lobby. Lots of high vantage points.
- 很好  - 好了 我们来看一下它的布局
- I like it.  - Okay. Let's take a look.
您的账单
Here you go.
我来付
I'll take it.
谢了
Cheers.
你祈祷过吗？
Do you ever pray?
祈祷过很长时间 但从未收到答复
Been a long time. No one answered.
就放弃了
I gave HP-
可悲
That's sad.
在我家乡那里 牧师和恶棍没什么区别
Where I come from, priests
and crooks, they're all the same.
你有梦想吗？
Do you dream?
没有
No.
考虑过将来吗？
Ever think about your future?
没有 将来来得其实够快了 你呢？
No, it will come soon enough.
And you?
我只想离开 离开这座城市
I just want out. Out of the city.
离开眼下的生活
Out of the life.
和一个值得信任的人在一起
With someone I can trust.
要怎样才能让你信任？
Trust to do what?
当我离开的时候 能为我点一盏灯
Light a candle for me
when I'm gone.
今晚的货色不错啊
Our selection for the evening.
我忙着呢
I'm busy.
我想你会愿意见这个人
I think you wanna see this.
劳烦各位离开
I need the room. Please.
既然你信不过那个黑鬼
You don't trust the African
to come through.
我准备了这个候补
So I got us a backup.
我们这位朋友在这个地区
为本尼·布莱克经营皮肉生意
Our friend here runs girls
for Benny Black in the district.
他看见那张照片 说他认识那个拿十字弓的家伙
He saw the picture. He says he
knows the guy with the crossbow.
你认识那个杀了我弟弟的畜生？
You know the animal
that killed my brother?
是的 先生 我们是邻居
Yes, sir. We're neighbors.
等等
Wait.
小心点
Be careful.
不好意思 这是怎么回事？
Excuse me, what's going on here?
女士 我们是警察
Police, madam. Police.
形势已经在我们掌控之中 你可以回你的办公室了
The situation's under control.
You can step back into your office.
回你的办公室去
Get back into your office.
放老实点 不然我又要用这个对付你了 懂吗？
You can come quietly,
or I can use this again, okay?
带他走
Move it.
你那个胖胖的朋友打算宁死不屈来着
Your fat friend tried to hold out.
他确实是这么做的 但到最后…
He really did. But finally...
…他嚎得他妈像个女高音似的
...he sang like a fucking soprano.
把你的全部底细都供出来了 还有你躲在乡下的小窝
Told me all about you
and your little country hideaway.
谁知道呢？说不定我会去探望一下你老婆
Who knows?
Maybe I pay our girl a visit.
干得漂亮
Excellent work.
客户非常满意
The client is very pleased.
不验一下货吗？
You're not going to examine them?
我信得过你
I trust you.
我还有一单活儿…
I have another prospect.
我要休息一阵子
I'm going to take some time off.
喂？
Hello?
伙计 是打给你的
My friend. It's for you.
- 喂  - 你女朋友真讨人喜欢
- Hello.  - Your friend has been a lovely hostess.
她就在这呢
Here she is.
我听说你这人很冷酷
I hear you are a hard man.
但就算是像为我们这样冷酷的人 也有些在乎的东西
But even hard men like us
have something we care about.
比如说…
For example...
…我爱我的弟弟
...I loved my brother very much.
就是那个被你杀掉的弟弟
The brother that you murdered.
我们做个交易吧
I suggest an exchange.
用你来换这个妞
You for her.
你根本没有选择
You don't really have a choice.
就像一个智者说过的：
As a wise man once said:
我们都受制于自己的感情
We are all prisoners
of our own passions.
你看错我了
You're wrong about me.
我不会受制于任何事
I'm not a prisoner of anything.
他想赌一把
He wanted to gamble.
我告诉过他这招对你没用
I told him it was impossible
to get to you.
你暗算我
You went behind my back.
- 我们的合作玩完了  - 哦 别这样
-It's done between you and I.  - Oh, come.
你反应过激了
You're overreacting.
要是真的等我反应过激了 你就死定了
If I overreacted, you'd be dead.
告诉我钱在哪 我好给你个痛快
Tell me where the money is
and I'll make it quick.
放我走吧 我会就此消失
Just let me go right now.
You'll never see me again.
要是我们不呢？
And if we don't?
那我他妈就干掉你
Then I'll fucking kill you.
放松点啦
Easy.
先把钱弄回来再说
Let's get our money back first.
好吧 最后一次机会
Okay, last chance.
喏 这是伽柏 他是个行家
Now, Gabor here, he's an expert.
他能让你有好受的
He can make this last quite a while.
钱在哪里？
Where's the money?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know
what you're talking about.
你跟他约好了吗？
He's expecting you?
我正盼着你改主意呢
I was hoping you'd reconsider.
他们把弗林特弄哪去了
I need to know
where they took Flint.
这可不是你的一贯作风
You're breaking your own code.
只凭一时感情用事便去冒险
Risking your life
because of feelings.
如果没有感情 我怎么算是活着的？
If I don't feel, am I really alive?
经过这么长时间 我以为我了解你
And all this time,
I thought I understood you.
你我之间再了解不过了
You and I understand
each other perfectly.
我们都用钱说话
We speak the same language.
告诉我弗林特在哪 别浪费时间了
I need to know where Flint is.
We're losing time.
我不要报酬
I don't want payment.
我这么做只是想修复我们的合作关系
I do this in hopes
of repairing our partnership.
我确信这段关系未来会持续很久 且有利可图
Which I'm certain will have
a long and profitable future.
如果我没记错的话 保罗先生提议过…
If memory serves me correctly,
Mr. Polo suggested...
…他侄子的废弃工厂很适合用来审问弗林特
...his cousin's old factory as a suitable
place to question Mr. Flint.
钱在哪里？
Where's the money?
罗兰
Roland.
罗兰 罗兰 救我！
Roland. Roland, help!
好了
0K8)'-
钱在哪里？我不会再问一遍了
Where's the money?
I won't ask again.
在哪？
It's where?
花光了
Spent it.
杀了他
Finish it.
伽柏
Gabor.
- 混蛋  - 好的 靠拢过来
- Shit.  - Okay, hold it together.
靠拢过来
Just hold it together.
- 你去查看那边  - 我不去
- You go check that way.  - I'm not going out there.
- 什么？  - 我说我不去
- What?  - I'm not going out there.
什么？上帝——
What? Jesus Chri--
那么 干点有用的事 好吧？
Okay, do something
useful then, yeah?
看好——
Take care of--
出来 不然我立马杀了他
Come out now,
or I'll shoot him right here.
出来 不然我炸掉他的头
Show yourself or I swear to God
I'll blow his fucking head off.
早该这么做了
Should have let me be.
你陷害我
You set me up.
我错了 现在我回来了
It was a mistake. I came back.
是的
Yeah, you did.
撤诉状
- 什么事  - 不好意思打扰了 先生 还是没有消息
- Yes.  - Sorry to interrupt, sir. Still no word.
- 再试试  - 是弗林特的事？
- Keep trying.  - it's Flint, isn't it?
他们去解决他 现在却不见了踪影
They went to finish him
and now they're missing.
这不关你的事
It's no concern of yours.
哦 不 我认为弗林特先生跟我们俩都有关系
Oh, no, I think Mr. Flint
is a shared concern of ours.
我们都让他的日子不好过
We have both caused him
a great deal of grief.
而且凭他的能力…
And left to his own devices...
…他一定会不择手段地报复…
...he will stop at nothing
to return the favor...
…我们俩
...to both of us.
你还有什么办法？
What can you do
that we're not already doing?
你AK枪用得不错
You're pretty good with the AK.
我早就觉得你不只是会耍刀
Thought you were more
of a knife man.
- 工欲善其事 必先利其器  - 你当然有这个权利
- Use the best tool for the job.  - You got that right.
事实上 那是你的枪
It was one of yours, actually.
- 喂？  - 帕瓦勒斯夫人 是我 罗兰
- Hello?  - Mrs. Pavlescu, it's me, it's Roland.
我想让你现在把安娜转移出屋子
I need you to get Anna
out of the house now.
什么？喂？
What? Hello?
喂？
Hello?
电话线被切断了
Line was cut.
喂？
Hello?
- 掉头  - 好的
- Turn around.  - Okay.
- 喂？  - 再见
- Hello?  - Goodbye.
他们把窗帘拉上了
They drew the curtains.
阻挡了视线
Cutting off lines of sight.
前门至少两个人把守
At least two at the front.
好的 得把他们引出来
All right, we're gonna have
to draw them out.
扔手榴弹
Grenades.
我老婆也在那里
My wife's in there.
我想我对解救人质不太擅长
I guess I'm not too good
with hostage situation.
欢迎回家 弗林特先生 查看一下你的网络摄像头
Welcome home, Mr. Flint.
Check your webcam.
她太美了
So beautiful.
你他妈的别碰她
Don't you fucking touch her.
什么？信号不太好
What? Connection not too good.
我来把事情变得简单点
I'm gonna make this real simple.
如果你和你的朋友…
If you and your friend...
…15分钟内不缴械投降的话…
...don't surrender to us
unarmed in 15 minutes...
…首先呢 我会让我的手下轮流上她
...first, I will let each of my men
take turns with her.
然后我要你眼睁睁看着我活剥她的皮
Then I'll let you watch
while I skin her alive.
要是连这都不能弄醒她 她就真的醒不过来了
And if that doesn't wake her up,
nothing will.
15分钟
Fifteen minutes.
你想怎么办？
What do you want to do?
童话之所以会终结…
The thing about fairy tale endings...
…是因为它们都是扯淡
...is that they're bullshit.
我的命已经在你手里了 别伤害她
You got me. Just leave her alone.
听我说啊
I tell you what.
我最后上她一次
I do her last.
不过这次你不用看着
That way you don't have
to watch this time.
我给你钱
I have money.
多少钱也买不回我弟弟的命
No money
can bring my brother back.
但你可以用另一种方式来偿还
But you will pay in a different way.
慢慢还
And slowly.
我有1200万
I have 12 million.
扯淡
Bullshit.
给他看看
Show him.
这大概就值120万
That's about 1.2 million.
我还藏了比这多十倍的
I got 10 times more hidden inside.
扯淡
Bullshit.
放我走 我就拿给你看
You let me leave
and I'll show it to you.
- 你究竟在搞什么？  - 什么？
- What the hell are you doing?  - What?
你他妈想干什么？
What the hell is this?
命运就是如此
That's life.
命运？什么鬼命运？
That's life? That's fucking life?
我老婆就在那边
That's my wife over there.
你却跟我讲什么命运？
You're telling me that's fucking life?
慢着
Wait.
他是你的
He's yours.
起来
Get up.
求她
Now beg.
去死
Fuck you.
- 求她  - 不
- Beg.  - No.
求她
Beg her.
原谅我
Please forgive me.
大声点儿
You can do better than that.
Louden
原谅我！
Forgive me!
- 再说一遍  - 原谅我！
- Again.  - Please forgive me!
很好
That's good.
现在只剩下一个问题
There's just one problem.
她听不到
She can't hear you.
对不起 亲爱的
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
对不起
I'm sorry.
都结束了
It's over.
还没有
Not yet.
不能保证百分百成功 这是种新的疗法
There's no guarantee of success.
It's a new procedure.
而且代价高昂
And it is quite expensive.
哦 不用担心这个问题
Oh, don't worry about that.
我付得起
I've got the money.
好的 那么 我们得立刻开始治疗
Okay, then,
we should start right away.
我只是想离开
I just want out.
离开这座城市 离开眼下的生活
Out of the city. Out of the life.
和一个值得信任的人在一起
With someone I can trust.
要怎样才能让你信任？
Trust to do what?
当我离开的时候 能为我点一盏灯
Light a candle for me
when I'm gone.